行尸走肉前情回顾
Previous on AMC The Wlaking Dead.
我已经漂泊了好几个月了
I've been on the road for a couple of months.
你自己?
By yourself?
是啊
Yeah.
你叫什么?
You got a name?
我叫Brian Heriot
Brian Heriot.
必须要找个更安全的地方 你来帮我们找
There has to be someplace better, and you're gonna help us find it.
快过来
Come here.
该你了 小宝贝
Your move, pumpkin.
我在思考
I'm thinking.
Mitch 拿着
Mitch, grab that.
上去
Go on.
你不能只是思考
You can't think forever.
早晚都要有行动
Sooner or later, you've got to make a move.
你从来都不让我赢
You never let me win anyway.
要是我让你 就不算你真的赢了
Well, that wouldn't be winning.
我爸就是这么跟我说的
That's what my daddy used to say.
他以前下棋也总是赢我
He used to beat me at chess, too.
该死 他什么事情都赢我
Heck, he used to beat me at everything.
你认识他吗?
You know this guy?
你爸是不是很严厉?
Was your dad mean?
有时候是的
Sometimes.
那你很调皮吗?
Were you bad?
有时候是的
Sometimes.
这段时期你一直都在漂泊?
So you've been on the road all this time?
嗯
Yeah.
没事吧 Brian?
You okay, Brian?
怎么了 宝贝?
What is it, pumpkin?
我很调皮吗?
Am I bad?
说什么呢?
What?
嘿
Hey.
你怎么会那么想?
Why would you think that?
我爸爸总是对我很严厉
My dad was always mean to me.
嘿 你是个好孩子
Hey, you're good.
真的
You are.
一英里外我们有个营地
We've got a camp about a half a mile from here.
绝对不行 Martinez
Hell, no, Martinez.
那里已经有很多人了
We got too many mouths as it is.
看在他们带着一个孩子的份儿上
They got a kid for Christ's sake.
嘿 如果你想和我们一起回去 必须答应两个条件
Hey, if you do come back with us, there's two things you got to accept.
第一 听我指挥
One, I'm in charge.
第二 顾好自己
Two, no deadweight.
每个人都是这样
That goes for everyone.
同心协力 否者就把你踢出去
Contribute or be cast out.
能接受吗
Can you live with that,
Brian啊?
Brian?
你 我 妈妈 还有Tara阿姨
You, me, your mom, and Aunt Tara,
我们都会平安的
we're gonna be okay.
因为我们是好孩子?
'Cause we're good?
是吗?
All of us?
该你了
Your turn.
Brian 听到了吗?
Brian?
该你走了
It's your turn.
我在思考
I'm thinking.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 波特妹子 时间轴: pisces夜
翻译: 初见 桃茜茜 失眠影
校对: 潇妹纸
行尸走肉 第四季 第七集
你今天要出去吗?
You going out there today?
去弄点生活用品
Supply run.
和Martinez还有Dolgen兄弟一起去
Martinez and the Dolgen brothers.
我要在营地里建一个护士站
I'm gonna set up a nurses' station for the camp.
他们需要
They need one.
- 对不起 Lily 这里...  - 别说了
- I'm sorry, Lily. This place is...  - Stop it.
我希望我们能住在一个更好的地方
I wanted something better for us.
这个营地很好
This camp is good.
我们会把它建得更好
We'll make it better.
鱼钓得怎么样?
How's the fishing?
池塘里根本没有鱼
There isn't any. Pond's dead.
一潭死水
As a doornail.
但我们还能抓到兔子 鼬鼠
We still got rabbits, skunks,
和负鼠什么的
some possum out here.
你最好小心点 独眼Bri
You better watch your ass, One Eye Bri.
我们没走错方向吧?
You sure we're headed in the right direction?
只要Howard的地图没画错
If Howard's map is right.
他们应该把他拖来 这样更保险
We should have dragged his ass out here to make sure.
他老得已经走不动了
He's an old man. He can barely walk.
所以我太才说把他"拖"来
That's why I said dragged.
希望我们没白忙活一场
Hope this is worth it.
希望那家伙也是一个活命主义者
Supposedly this guy was a survivalist type.
他的小屋里也许有我们需要的
His cabin might have stuff we can use.
他可能还活着
Hell, maybe he's still alive.
我才不管呢
I won't keep my fingers crossed.
嘿 独眼 你在干嘛?
Hey, One Eye. What you doing?
骗子
这是什么?
What the hell is this?
有人把另一个人惹毛了
Somebody pissed somebody off.
谁管呢?
Who gives a shit?
这家伙算是高枕无忧了
That guy's got nothing to worry about anymore.
走吧
Let's go.
- 伤口挺深  - 没什么事的
- It's a deep cut.  - No, that's nothing, ma'am.
我不小心割到了 没事的
I just got cute with my knife, that's all. I'll be fine.
那...
So...
我叫Alicia
Alicia.
Alicia 好的
Alicia. Right.
你以前是海军陆战队员吗?
You in the Marines or something?
陆军后备队
Army. In the reserves.
那是M4卡宾枪吧?
An M4, huh?
你不喜欢它?
You don't approve?
别误会我
I mean, don't get me wrong,
近身搏斗M4卡宾枪很管用
an M4 is great for close combat,
但至于野战?
but as a field weapon?
在尘土飞扬的战场上 还是算了吧
With all that dirt and dust, no, thanks.
我也不喜欢大型枪械
I've never really been into big guns anyway.
我更喜欢史密斯威森
I'm more of a Smith & Wesson gal.
更干脆 明白吗?
Less fuss, you know?
你总是这么磨叽吗?
You always this full of shit?
是的
Yes, I am.
强奸犯
杀人犯
他把自己结果了
Took himself out.
你觉得是他开枪打死了那些士兵吗?
You think he's the one who 86'd those military guys?
- 他的脑袋还在  - 算是吧
- He still has his head.  - Some of it, anyway.
看看里面有什么
Let's see what he's got inside.
听到了吗? 里面有一个
You hear that? There's one in there.
肯定是被困在里面了
Must be stuck if it ain't coming out.
进去吗?
We going in?
你打算等到吓尿完了再进去?
You want us to wait till you finish pissing in your pants?
- 我没...  - 别废话了
- No, I'm...  - Cut the chatter.
嘿 进去吧
Hey. Let's go.
- 声音很近了  - 别出声
- It's close.  - Quiet.
- 出来了  - 闭嘴
- It's out.  - Shut up.
哦! 放开我!
Oh! Get it off of me!
放开我! 放开我!
Get it off of me! Get it off of me!
放开我!
Get it off of me!
天啊!
Jeez!
Pete啊!
Pete!
如果你一个人掉到坑里
If it was just you in that pit,
我绝不会把你带回营地
I wouldn't have brought you into the camp.
要是你没和她在一起...
If it weren't for the people you were with...
那个小女孩...
the girl...
你和以前不一样了
You seem different now.
你变了
Changed.
是吗?
Are you?
是的
I am.
很好
Good.
这家伙有不少好东西
The guy had some good stuff.
罐头食品
Canned food.
哦
Ooh.
有啤酒喝了
We got beer.
这里怎么了?
Man, what happened here?
这间小木屋里到底出过什么事?
I mean, what the hell was going on in this cabin?
他把那些行尸关在这里?
Was he storing those biters?
那是他的妻子和孩子
They were his wife and kid, man.
不 他们是行尸
No, they were biters.
那些断头是怎么回事?
What about those heads?
估计是找事找错人 被人干掉了
Belonged to the guys who did the wrong thing to the wrong man.
还是不要猜测了
Probably best not to think too much about it.
最好听独眼Bri的 Pete
Better listen to one eye Bri, Pete.
我分辨不出来他在眨眼还是抛媚眼
I can never tell if he's winking or blinking.
但你知道怎么领导大家 是吧 Bri?
But you know how to regulate, don't you, Bri?
他总是这样一言不发吗 Martinez?
He was always like this, Martinez?
没错 冷冰冰的
Oh, yeah. Ice in the veins.
你应该看看他白天的表现
You should have seen him back in the day.
那你们呢?
What about you fellas, huh?
你们以前是干什么的?
What did you do before it all changed?
我...
I was...
我以前开车送冰淇淋
I was an ice cream truck driver.
然后自我增值 成为一名坦克手
Till I upgraded my life and I became a tank operator
为美军效力
for the US Army.
嗬哈!
Hoo-ah!
嗬哈
Hoo-ah.
然后世事突变
Then when everything went tits up,
我开着自己的座驾逃生了
I got the hell out and took my ride with me.
世界末日并不糟糕
End of the world don't mean shit
一辆坦克闯天下
when you got a tank.
我也是军人
I was Army, too.
驻扎在本宁堡
Stationed out of Fort Benning.
这些怪物出现后 在那里留守了一阵子
Stayed for a while after it all started.
这就是Pete
That's my Pete.
他过于忠诚 不懂变通
He's too loyal to bounce.
你呢 Brian?
What about you, Brian?
你以前是做什么工作的?
What did you do when it all went bad?
我就是幸存了
I survived.
什么 你爸是天主教的神父?
Wait, your father was a Catholic priest?
是的
That's right.
所以神父变成父亲?
So the father became a daddy?
这在当时给教会造成了一些争议
It caused some problems with the Church a little bit.
Brian以前听说过这些事的
This is all stuff Brian's heard before.
我们从前总是待在一起
We spent a lot of time out there together.
你做得很不错 这个营地
You've done all right here. I mean this camp.
自这些事情发生后 我还是第一次感到安全
It's the first time I've felt safe since all this started.
我和Brian从前居住的地方也挺好的
The place Brian and I lived before kind of worked.
我想着重新建造一个
I guess I wanted that again.
你们的旧营地 听起来很不错啊
Sounds like your old camp was pretty sweet.
你们那里有筑围墙的吧?
You guys had walls, right?
是啊 是的
Yeah. Yeah, it was...
那是个好地方
it was a good place.
这里也是个好地方 对吧?
This place is good, too, right?
你懂的
You know it.
希望有一天你能把这些轶事都告诉我
I want to hear all about it someday.
Brian什么都不肯说
Brian won't say a word.
我说了 往事不必再提
I say leave the past in the past.
好了 这是长久以后的第一次
Well, for the first time in a long time,
- 我要烂醉如泥了  - Tara
- I'm shitfaced.  - Tara.
抱歉 Megan 你可别学这话啊
Sorry. Megan, don't say that, okay?
- 你想出去走走吗  - 好的
- You want to get out of here?  - Yeah.
谢谢你这顿饭 更感谢那些酒
Thanks for the dinner. Double thanks for the suds.
好的 不客气
Yeah. Boom. There you go.
- 注意安全  - 好
- Be safe.  - Yep.
我想我也该走了
I think, um... I think I'm gonna go.
真的吗? 我这里还有两罐啤酒
You sure? I got a couple of skunky beers left.
哇
Whoa.
我没事 谢谢
I'm good, thanks.
Brian 屋顶又漏水了
Brian, the roof's leaking again.
你应该把那修一修
You should fix that, man.
我会修的
I'll do that.
再见 小娃娃
Later, muneca.
差点忘了 给你个惊喜
Almost forgot. Got a surprise for you.
哇
Whoa.
啊 没中
Aw, damn it.
递个球给我
Hand me another one.
你知道他死了 对吧?
You know he's dead, right?
你是指Shumpert?
Shumpert?
离开伍德伯里之后 他就变了
He was never the same after Woodbury.
噢!
Oh!
他变得非常鲁莽
Yeah. He got reckless.
他在那边被行尸咬了
Biter took a piece of him right over there.
可是他并没有挣扎
I swear, he didn't try to get out of the way.
是我亲手把他杀了
I put him down myself.
就在那里
Right over there.
真是遗憾
I'm sorry.
有些事情 你是回不去了
There's some things you just can't come back from.
却对你产生深远的影响
They become a part of who you are.
你要么接受 要么就与之抗争
Either you live with them or you don't.
你似乎就相当能接受
Well, you seem to be living with them pretty well.
你也是
So are you.
那个家庭 让你重新找回自己
That family, they brought you back.
你很幸运 可我不行...
You're lucky. I couldn't...
我做不来 我不敢去冒险
I couldn't do that again. Couldn't risk it.
知道终将会失去他们 我夜不能眠
Couldn't sleep at night knowing I was gonna lose them.
我不会失去他们的
I'm not gonna lose them.
是的
Yeah.
怎么 你认为你不能保护这个地方?
What, you don't think you can keep this place safe?
我会尽力
I'll try.
但愿我们能为突发情况做好准备
Hopefully we'll be prepared for whatever comes.
现在有你在这儿
Now you're here,
也许我们俩能够共同管理
maybe we can share the crown a little.
天啊
Oh, Jesus.
我以前真该去上高尔夫球课...
I should have taken some golf lessons before the...
我们走
Come on, let's go.
来
Come on.
我不想这样的!
I don't wanna do it!
我不想这样的! 我不想这样的!
I don't want it! I don't want it!
听到没? 我不想这样的!
You hear me? I don't want it, damn it!
我不想这样的!
I don't want it.
Brian 我们回来了!
Brian, we're home!
Megan 他睡了
Megan, he's sleeping.
Brian 怎么了?
Brian?
你全身发抖
You're shaking.
怎么了?
What is it?
我做了个恶梦 没什么的
I just had a bad dream, that's all.
是什么恶梦呢?
What was it?
想不起来了
I can't remember.
听着!
Listen up!
我们今天早上在坑里
We found what was left of Martinez
发现Martinez的尸体残渣
in a pit this morning.
他似乎当时正在打高尔夫球
Looks like he was hitting some golf balls,
然后喝醉了
he got drunk,
失足掉进坑里
he fell in.
那现在怎么办?
So now what?
将由我接管营地
I'm taking leadership of the camp.
- 不可以  - 先别吵! 冷静!
- No. No.  - Hold on now. Hold on now!
应该由我们投票选出领导 对吧?
We should vote on who leads, right?
- 没错  - 你不能就这样接管
- Yeah.  - You can't just take over.
- 闭嘴 小贱人  - 什么?
- Shut your mouth, you little bitch.  - What?
- 嘿!  - 嘿 冷静!
- Hey!  - Hey, calm down!
请大家冷静
Calm down, all of you.
此时此刻 我们最需要的就是彼此
We need each other now more than ever.
要想挺过这些困境 我们唯一能做的
The only way we get through this, through any of this,
就是团结一致
is together.
现在只是暂时性的
Now this is temporary.
我们会找到个投票选举的方法
We'll find some kind of way to do a vote
再多等几天
in the next couple of days.
现在 一切活动照常
For now, it's business as usual.
好吗?
Okay?
你听到他说的了
You heard the man.
快走!
Move!
好吗?
Please?
带上装备 我们去打猎
Gear up. We're going on a hunt.
限额配给 修围栏 医疗用品
Rationing, fences, medical supplies.
大家有一堆事情等着我帮他们解决
There are 100 questions and people are looking to me for answers.
领导也不是一件易事
Well, it's hard to lead.
是啊 我需要帮忙
Yeah, I could use some help.
嘿
Hey.
有多少人?
How many?
十个
10.
也许更少
Maybe less.
不过他们有很多物资
They got a lot of supplies, though.
也许我们可以把他们接收进来
Maybe we should take 'em in.
你疯了吗?
Are you crazy?
我们的物资本来就不够供给了
We barely got enough to go around as it is.
Pete 我知道你不想伤害任何人
Look, Pete, I know you don't want to hurt nobody.
我也不想 但是我们需要这些物资
Neither do I, but we need those supplies.
我们直冲过去
Now let's just go over there
拿上我们需要的 然后回家
and take what we need and go home.
不为难他们
No rough stuff.
- 你打算抢他们的?  - 有何不可?
- You want to rob 'em?  - Why not?
我们需要他们的物资
We need their stuff.
他们手上有枪 但如果我们下手得快...
They got guns, but if we roll up on 'em quick...
不
No.
不行 我们自己可以找到物资
No, we can find our own supplies.
走吧
Come on.
- 这真是可笑  - 我们收获不错
- What a joke.  - We did all right.
是啊 就两只破松鼠 还有一些炼奶
Yeah, a couple of damn squirrels, some condensed milk.
你想我怎么样? 我在尽力了
What do you want from me? I'm trying here.
嘿
Hey.
你要去哪?
Where you going?
该死
Son of a bitch.
该死!
Son of a bitch!
不是行尸干的
This wasn't biters.
是人干的
People did this.
肯定是刚刚洗劫了这里
Must have just happened.
我们本来可以抢到那些补给的
We would have had those supplies.
你竟然在担心补给?
You're worried about supplies?
这些人死了 Mitch
These people are dead, Mitch.
你说得对 他们死了!
You're damn right they're dead!
无论谁干的 他们都得死
That was gonna happen either way.
现在某些人抢了本该属于我们的补给
Now some other group's got our stuff.
Mitch 住手 Mitch!
Mitch. Mitch, no!
他本来有救的
He might have lived.
现在没了
Might have.
给你 需要这个吗?
Here you go. Need this?
Brian 出了什么事?
Brian, what's going on?
- 马上收拾东西  - 出了什么事?
- Pack your things, now.  - What's happening?
- 在这儿等我 宝贝  - 嘿
- Hold on, baby. - Hey.
收拾衣服 带点食物 快点
Grab your clothes, pack some food. Come on.
妈妈?
Mommy?
- Brian 等等  - 去找Tara
- Brian, stop.  - Get Tara.
我们得离开 这里不安全了
We need to leave. It isn't safe here anymore.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我们不能就这么走掉
We can't just run off.
我是营地唯一的护士 Tara还有Alicia
I'm the only nurse in camp. Tara's got Alicia.
Megan怎么办?
What about Megan?
听着 事情会变得非常糟糕
Look, things are about to go very wrong here.
我之前遇到过 所以不能让你和Megan也经历这些
It's happened to me before. I can't put you and Megan through that.
不能再失去你
Can't lose you again.
那Pete怎么办?
What about Pete?
你也说了 他是个好人
You said he was a good man.
- 我看错了  - 但...
- Well, I was wrong.  - But...
你相信我吗?
Do you trust me?
你相信我吗 Lily?
Do you trust me, Lily?
那就收拾东西
Then pack your things.
我们今晚就走 好吗?
We're leaving tonight, okay?
去吧
Come on.
妈妈
Mommy.
我们要去哪儿?
Where are we going?
- Alicia  - 也许你该开慢点
- Alicia.  - Maybe you should slow down.
不 我不明白 我不明白是怎么回事
No, I don't understand this. I don't understand this.
嘿 我们在一起就行 好吗?
Hey, we're together, okay?
我们在营地什么都有 有食物 有住处
We have everything back there. We have food, we have shelter.
- Brian  - 天啊
- Brian. - Oh, my God.
待在车里
Just stay in the car.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
活下去
Surviving.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
Mitch的事情
About Mitch.
进来
Come in.
我知道事情会变成这样
I knew this was coming.
我一直想方设法不让他惹麻烦...
I've been getting him out of trouble my...
Pete在哪儿?
Where's Pete?
他死了
He's dead.
你也要杀了我 对吧?
You gonna kill me, too, now?
是吗? 就为了营地的那个老家伙?
Huh? For the old guy at the camp?
抽烟吗?
Smoke?
你为什么要杀了我哥哥?
Why did you do my brother?
那个营地的事 你说对了
You were right about that camp.
我们应该抢走他们的补给
We should have taken their supplies.
你杀没杀那老头 我不在乎
I don't care that you killed the old man.
你哥哥那种人总是想做正确的事
Men like your brother, always doing the right thing,
哪怕要以自己人的生命为代价
even at the cost of their own people.
好了 抽根烟吧
Go on. Have a cigarette.
我戒了
I quit.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
还记得我第一次抽烟的时候
I remember the first smoke I ever had.
我和哥哥藏在车库里
Me and my brother huddled in the garage
抽着我爸的好彩香烟
puffing on one of my dad's Lucky Strikes.
他肯定是闻到了烟味 所以他闯进来
He must have smelled the smoke, because he came barging in
想狠狠揍我们一顿
looking to beat up on us.
但我哥哥挡在了我面前
But my brother got between us.
说是他偷的
Said he stole them.
那是谎话 其实是我偷的
Wasn't true. It was me.
但那是我哥哥
But that was my brother.
是个英雄
Hero.
他被打得两眼青肿 还被打断了一根肋骨
He got two black eyes and a broken rib for that.
我也被打了
And I got beat anyway.
抽一根吧
Take one.
现在是我管事
I'm running things now,
所以我会竭尽全力 保护这个营地
and I will do everything it takes to protect this camp.
如果你跟我一伙儿 我保证
Now, if you join me, I promise you
你永远不用担心自己做的事
you will never have to worry about whether you were doing
是对是错
the right thing or the wrong thing.
因为我们
Because we will do
说了算
the only thing.
Pete的事 怎么跟营地的人交代?
What are we gonna tell the camp about Pete?
我们就说在找补给的时候 他为了救我们
We'll tell them he died on a supply run
牺牲了自己
saving our asses.
你觉得他们真的会相信吗?
You think they're really gonna believe that?
人们会相信想相信的东西
People believe what they want to believe.
大家都爱英雄
Everybody loves hero.
营地防守线怎么样了?
How's the perimeter coming?
很好 我们有车辆沿着整个营地外围巡逻
It's good. We got cars ringing almost the entire camp.
我觉得再去清理几次 就能有个非常好的缓冲地带了
I think a few more runs, we should have ourselves a nice little buffer.
- 行尸呢?  - 他们来了 就烧了他们
- And the pits?  - They keep coming, we keep burning them.
我不知道是不是热量的关系
I don't know if it's the heat or what,
但最近他们来得越来越多了
but there have been a hell of a lot more of them lately.
- 武器呢?  - 很充足
- And the armory?  - Solid.
我把营地的武器都集中起来
I rounded up all the ammo in camp.
正式存放在弹药库了
We're officially stocked in the bullet department.
但还是要告诉你们的人
Still, tell your crews
出去找补给的时候只能用弓箭
supply runs are arrow only from now on.
子弹是奢侈品
Gunshots are a luxury.
我们迟早会需要的
Sooner or later we're gonna need 'em.
没错 而且不仅仅是用来对付行尸
That's right, and not just for the biters.
我 Mitch和Pete
Mitch and I and Pete,
我们看到了外面人的所作所为
we saw what people can do out there.
如果遇到陌生人 就避开
You come across strangers, you just avoid them.
回来这里 告诉我们是在哪儿见到的 好吗?
Come back here and tell us where you saw them, okay?
出发
Let's go.
也许我们能找到个更好的地方
Maybe we can find a better place.
要知道 如果...
You know, if...
我们愿意为之战斗的话
we're willing to fight for it.
我们不需要再找更好的地方
We don't need to find a better place.
这里就是家
This is home.
你做鬼 Tara阿姨
You're it, Aunt Tara.
什么? 我不能陪你玩 还得守卫呢
What? I can't be it. I'm on guard duty.
我得做个负责任的成年人
I have to be a responsible adult.
- 你做鬼  - 去追她
- You're it.  - Go get her.
- 不公平!  - 快跑 Megan
- No fair!  - Run, Megan.
你不用一个人做这些
You don't have to do this alone.
抓到你了
Caught you.
Tara阿姨!
Aunt Tara!
Megan 坚持住!
Megan!
Tara阿姨! 救命!
Aunt Tara! No!
- 妈妈!  - Megan!
- Mommy!  - Megan!
- 是你的错!  - 不是
- It's your fault!  - It's not.
没事了 没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
没事了
It's okay.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 波特妹子 时间轴: pisces夜
翻译: 初见 桃茜茜 失眠影
校对: 潇妹纸